# Muthineni Vinod

## CONTACT

#### Address

Madhapur,Hyderabad,Telangana Phone: 9966509511 Email:vinodmuthineni2@gmail.com

#### **LANGUAGES**

**English** 

Telugu

Hindi

## **TOOLS**

Google Analytics, Ahrefs, Page Speed Insights, Moz, SEMrush, Google Keyword Planner, Google Search Console, Uber Suggest 

## **SUMMARY**

Organize the Search Engine Optimization responsibilities for both company and client websites. To join and work for a company that will enable me to demonstrate, improve, and use my expertise in digital marketing for the advancement of the company and my career.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## Senior SEO Executive

09/2022 - Ongoing

## Medico Healthcare Services & Technologies

Hyderabad

Medical billing service in Hyderabad, Telangana

· Performing competitor analysis.

Monitoring site traffic and back links.

On-page and off-page optimization.

Perform SEO audits for client websites, identify keyword optimization opportunities, and provide recommendations to enhance web page.

Coordinate with clients to develop SEO strategy based on Google Analytics, keyword rankings, and competitive analysis.

Improving organic search results by increasing the search engine results.

Collaborated with internal teams to enhance design, usability, content and conversion points of websites and web properties.

Creating monthly reports for clients, preparing search engine ranking and traffic reports to assess areas of potential improvement.

Developed and implemented quality link-building strategies.

Optimized copy and landing pages for search engine marketing purposes.

Keyword Analysis, picking the right keywords, keyword density, keyword positioning, use of and keyword linking.

Perform On-page, Off-page and technical SEO audits and present recommendations to site.

Identifying SEO problems, analyze the cause and work on the issues.

Creating dynamic SEO strategies to exceed market competitors and meet client needs. Researched and implemented search engine optimization recommendations.

# Digital Marketing Executive

05/2019 - 08/2022

Hyderabad

#### **Kreativ Web Solutions**

Software Company

• Developing and implementing link building strategy.

Performing On page and Off page activities to boost page rankings.

Performing ongoing keyword discovery ,expansion and optimization.

Researching and implementing search engine optimization recommendations.

Researching and analyze of competitor backlinks using tools like (SEMRUSH). Preparing weekly and monthly reports.

Perform in-depth quantitative analyses of SEO performance and provide clear conclusions.

Working with Google Analytics and Webmaster tool.

Understanding the behavior of website users by using tools like Hotjar to get heatmaps, session recordings, and surveys.

Improving website – content, look & feel, lead generation performance, etc.

Measuring and improving key performance indicators such as traffic, clicks, conversion, contacts.

Working with content writer, to get best content for website and social media platforms. Working with the UI and development team to ensuring SEO best practices are properly implemented.

Email marketing using tools like Mail Chimp, Send Grid.

Posting in all social media channels using tools like Buffer and Hoot suit

Managing social presence and creating engaged communities across channels such as Facebook, Twitter, Pinterest, Instagram, and Linkedln.

# **EDUCATION**

MBA - Marketing

2016 - 2018

SLCS Inst of Engg And Technology Hyderabad.



# **EDUCATION**

NRI Institute of Technology Hyderabad

2010 - 2014

**B.Tech Electronics And Communications Engineering**